# CHRISTOPHER FARRELL

christopherfarrell.me

(518)275-3089

cxf1897@gmail.com

Software Engineer with knowledge in a variety of disciplines. Proven skills in software development, design, and maintenance. Experienced with designing software systems and planning for the future of those systems. Successful in communicating clearly with a variety of people and working in a team environment.

#### **Education:**

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, August 2015 - Rochester Institute of Technology

## **Experience:**

## **Software Engineer -** Oasis Systems, LLC.

Jun 2015 - Present

Worked in a team environment to develop software systems for the United States Air Force. Technologies: Node.js, AngluarJS, Typescript, MongoDB, ZeroMQ, Express, Jade, C++

## **Results:**

- Rewrote database handler code and removed extraneous calls to the database which improved performance by 50%.
- Created a UI that has a similar look and feel to the JIRA project and issues pages.
  - Wrote a variety of interactive editors that allow the user to click away to save.
- Wrote code to convert file into binary and send over a local area network when the file was put back together and saved to disk
- Created handlers to prevent the system from entering an error state and crashing if a component was taken down in the middle of running
- Created redirect system to prevent crashes from the system if a component wasn't running.

# Web Development Co-op - Nazareth College

Dec 2011 – Aug 2012

Developer for a variety of web applications for both internal and external use. Worked directly with customers and stakeholders to ensure that the best possible product was being delivered.

Technologies: Linux, Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Sensors Results:

- Decreased the overhead for the Registrar's office.
- Increased efficiency within the chemistry department.

## **Software Engineering Teaching Assistant - RIT**

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

Helped teach a class of 22 students the basics of eliciting requirements from the customer to releasing a finished product.

## **Projects:**

## **Virtual Meeting Outcome Facilitator (vMOF)**

Created a one-page web application for the MITRE corporation that was designed to mitigate the common problems that arose during meetings. Improved meeting efficiency through a variety of tasks aimed to streamline the regular tasks that were performed during a meeting.

## **Activities:**

#### **New Student Orientation - RIT**

Aug 2013/Aug 2014

Received extensive leadership training to help with the responsibility of incorporating 18 new students into the RIT community and helping them adjust to college.